Finding aid to the Department of German Studies Records CA.MS.00125
Smith College Archives
Department of German Studies Records
1900-1989
Smith College Archives
Smith College. Dept. of German Studies.
CA.MS.00125
0.417 linear feet (1 container)
This collection contains black and white photographs, course syllabi, mid-year and final exam questions, news releases, and programs from theatrical performances.
Biographical / Historical
The German Studies Department at Smith College was established in 1894. By the 1895-1896 academic year, its name changed to the German Language and Literature Department, and since 1994 it has been known as the German Studies Department.
Scope and Contents
The Department records, 1900s-1980s, contain materials describing the department's courses as well as its theatrical performances. Types of materials include black and white photographs of students and faculty, course syllabi, mid-year and final exam questions, news releases, and programs from theatrical performances.
Related Material
Researchers should also view:
RG 42. Faculty
90A-78Syllabi, course materials, honors program, 1969-1983
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Source unknown.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Smith College. Dept. of German Studies.
- General, 1930s-50s; 1986 (Box 1158, Folder 1)
- Courses- German 11-49, 1917-18; 1930s-60s (Box 1158, Folder 2)
- Courses- 100d, 1975-78 (Box 1158, Folder 3)
- Courses- 101-340, 1973-78 (Box 1158, Folder 4)
- Dramatics, 1900-1910; 1930s-40 (Box 1158, Folder 5)
- Untitled folder- photos, programs, news releases, 1900-1910; 1913; 1932 (Box 1158, Folder 6)
- German club- Deutsch Verein, 1930s-40 (Box 1158, Folder 7)
- German club- Plays- Der Nachtwaechter, 1911 (Box 1158, Folder 8)
- German club- Plays- Der fahrende Schueler im Paradies, 1911 (Box 1158, Folder 9)
- German club- Plays- Als Derlobte empfehlen sich, 1911; 1938 (Box 1158, Folder 10)
- Photographs, 1946; 1950s; 1980s (Box 1158, Folder 11)
- German House, 1930s (Box 1158, Folder 12)